Singer, Morton Papers 5011
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Morton Singer Papers
1945-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Singer, Morton
5011
13 cubic feet
13 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Case files, awards, and other legal documents of the arbitrator Morton Singer.
3338452
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, August 10, 2015
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 20, 2016
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States; Singer, Morton, 1906-1969
3338452
- A-C. (Box 1)
  - Ace Ice Cream, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allied Maintenance O.O. in with Loc. 366, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Local 815 and American feel Seype, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Automatic Sealing No. 119, 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - City of Beacon P.B.A., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Belock - Awards, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BELOCK, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - BELOCK, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - BELOCK, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - BELOCK, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - BELOCK - Transcript + Agreements, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bermuda Motor Car Renting with Local 522 I.B. of T, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Local 1278 I.A.M. AW - Borden Chemical, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Borg. Warner and Loc. 239 IBJ, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Boro Automatic vs. Peterson and Johanson, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bronx County Pharmaceutical Assoc. etc., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Busch Kredit Jewelry, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cagiano/ Automatic Coin + Vending Machine Employers Union Retail Clerks Intl. Association vs. Hirsch, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cagiano, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cagiano, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Capital Counter Display, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Capital Counter Display, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Chappaqua Teachers Ass., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cheesman-Elliot Co. vs. Paint Varnish and lacquer Workers Union AFL-CIO, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cigarette Merchandisers Assoc. vs. L. 805, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Clarkwood Services Corp. and ITU, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Coca Cola, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Commercial Con w Loc. 810, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- D-Independent. (Box 2)
  - Local 1146 RCIA vs. Double Kay Plumbing Co., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cropper Bus with Local 252, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Ebinger Baking Co. vs. L. 30, IUOE, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Local 48 I.P.E.U. and Empire Extrusions Corp., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Eugene's Valet vs Cleaners + Dyers 1.239, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Flohr Paint Co., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Franklin Gardens with 307 AFL, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Galin Press with Printing Unions, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Gen'l Analing and Film Lodge 1807 IAM+AW, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General Dynamics/Elec w Local 1 Roch. Ind. Workers, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Woodcraft Co. with Local 1702 ILA, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gilbert Carriers with Local 1021 ILGWU, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Graham Chemical with Local 535, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Industrial Div. - 1965-66 Atlantic Highlands L.1115, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Ind. Div. - 1965/66 Central General Hospital, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Indust. Div. 1965/66 - Docto5rs Hosp. Freeport, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Indust. Div. - 1965/66 Five Towns Nursing H./ Hotel Shalom/ Hudson View/ Inglemoor/ Lismore/ Lt. tides, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Ind. Div. - 1965/66 Mid-Island Hosp., 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ind. Div. - 1965-66 Pinehaven, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ind. Div. - 1965/66 Smithtown Gen. Hosp. Soth Shore Nursing Home, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Ind. Div. - 1966 - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ind. Div. 1967- Atlantic Highlands (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Ind. Div. 1967 - Atlantic Highlands / Ocean View, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Ind. Div. - 1967 - Central Gen. Hosp. / Countryside Nursing (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Ind. Div. 1967 - Five Towns Nursing Home (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Ind. Div. 1967 - Miami Hotel/ Mid-Island Hosp. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Ind. Div. 1967 - Ocean View Retreat (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ind. Div. 1967 Paramus Nursing Home (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Ind. Div. 1967 - Pinehaven (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Ind. Div. - 1967 - Promenade Hotel Royale (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Ind. Div. - 1967 - Scharf Hotel (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Indust. Div. - 1967 - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Ind. Div. 1968 - Atlantic Highlands/ Ocean View (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Ind. Div. 1968 - Bat Yam Hotel/ Blair House/ Breakers/ Brighton/ Carlton (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Ind. Div. 1968 - Crown Hotel (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Independent. (Box 3)
  - Ind. Div. 1968 - Doctors Hosp. / Fairfield Nursing (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ind. Div. 1968 - Five Town Nursing (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ind. Div. 1968 - Garden Restaurant/ Hotel Chai/ Hudson View Nursing H./ Ingelmoor (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ind. Div. 1968 - Lincoln Hotel/ Lesabell Lunch./ Mama's Kosher/ Miami Hotel/ Mid-Island Hosp. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ind. Div. 1968 - Nassau Nursing Home/ Palace Hotel/ Paradise Hotel (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ind. Div. 1968 - Pinehaven Sanit./ Promenade H. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ind. Div. 1968 - Royale Hotel (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ind. Div. 1968 - Sterling Nursing H. + Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ind. Div. 1969 - Atlantic Highlands/ Central Gen./ Crown/ Doctors Hosp. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ind. Div. 1969 - Hotel Shalom/ ILA Hotel/ Miami Hotel Ocean View Retreat/ Paradise Hotel/ Pinehaven Nursing Home/ Promenade Hotel (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Ind. Div. 1969 - Scharf's Smithtown Gen./ Sterling Nursing Home (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1969 Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Laundry Industry - Local 400 - N.L.R.B., 1952-1958 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Lipsett vs. Housewreck. L.95, 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Long Island Tobacco Co. vs. Paramour, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Luchow's vs. L.1, 1954-1959 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Lucky Rain Dear with Loc 815, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Mahopac Teachers Assoc. vs. Central School Dist. 1, Towns of Carmel + Putnam, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Mahopac Teacher's Assoc. vs. Central School Dist., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Margaretten with Local 408, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Westers Inc. with Local 222, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Local 517 with Nelson Bros., 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Palmer Plastics with Local 815, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Permatex Co. MCW Local 806 IBT, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Restaurant Industry 1957-1958 41 Foods/ 63 Nassau Rest. / 737 Third Ave. Corp. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Restaurant Industry 1957-58 Brenner - Freeport Cinemaster Films, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Restaurant Industry 1957-58 - coach House/ Flamingo Coffee Shop, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Restaurant Industry 1957-58 - Frank's Snackery Hamburg Bar Famous Luncheonette, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Restaurant Industry 1957-58 Simple's 7th Ave. Rest. Corp. Steakburger Steak Pit of Long Island, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Restaurant Industry 1957-58 Correspondence + Misc. Cases, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Restaurant - 1959 46th St. Food Shop 5th Ave. Corp./ A=M Lunch/ dam's Coffee Shop/ Bonnie's Food Shop/ Brenner - Freeport Effray Rest. (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Restaurant. (Box 4)
  - Restaurant Industry with Local 1115, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Restaurant Industry with Local 1115, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Restaurant Industry with Local 1115, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Restaurant. (Box 5)
  - Restaurant Industry File #6, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Restaurant Ind. With Local 1115, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Restaurant Union Local 1115, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Restaurant Industry - 1966 - (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Local 1115 Cases Last Folder, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Restaurant-Retail. (Box 6)
  - Rest. Industry, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Retail Women's Apparel Salespeople's Union, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Local 1115 Rest. Indus., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Local 1115 Cases ( Rest), 1969 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Local 340A Cases, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Retail Merchants of Long Island, Inc. with Local 340-A, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Local 340 A and ret. APP M-Ass'n., 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Long Island Merchants with Local 340-A ACWA, 1956-1958 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Retail Apparel Merchants Assoc. with Local 340 A-, 1959-1962 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Retail App. Merch. W Local 340-A, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Loc. 340 Cases #4, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Retail-Z. (Box 7)
  - Strauss Stores Corporation vs. David Livingston as Pres. Etc. (District US), 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - S. Rosengarten and Co. Inc. with Retail, Wholesale and CH Chain Store Food Employees Union Loc. 338, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - S. Rosengarten and Coo. Inc. with Fish, Sea Food Etc. Workers Loc. 635 AFL, 1953-1956 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Superior P.V.D. Magneto, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - #195 Superior Magneto and Independent Service Employees Union, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Local 102 w Toni's Italian Food, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Local 719 International Production Service and Sales Employees Union #308, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - U.S. Tire Supply w/ Local 721, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Ultra Slide, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Victory Container and Local 307, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Viking Merchants Ass'n w/ Loc 225 I.J.W.U. #205, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Local 78 w/ Yales and Towne, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - S. Rosengarten and Co. Inc. with Butchers Workers Local 640, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Local 340- Miscellaneous Cases., 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Local 340-A, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Rizzo and Sons with District w/ Local 27 IBT, 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Local 340-A Cases, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- 1956-1967. (Box 8)
  - Arbitration 1956 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Arbitration 1956 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Arbitration 1957 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Arbitration 1957 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Arbitration 1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Arbitration 1958 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Arbitration 1959 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Arbitration 1959 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Arbitration 1960 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Arbitration 1960 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Arbitration 1961 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Arbitration 1961 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Arbitration 1962 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Arbitration 1962 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Arbitration 1962 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Arbitration 1963 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Arbitration 1963 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Arbitration 1963 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Arbitration 1964 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Arbitration 1964 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Arbitration 1964 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Arbitration 1965 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Arbitration 1965 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Arbitration 1966 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Arbitration 1966 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Arbitration 1966 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Arbitration 1967 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Arbitration 1967 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Arbitration 1967 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Arbitration 1967 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- 1968-1969 - plus miscellaneous files. (Box 9)
  - Trial Memos and Briefs and Transcripts Herman vs Dean Jake Co./ Wertheimer Belger vs. Dis. 65 Kovacs v. Moss CNS vs. Arnold, 1959- 1960 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Memos - Transcripts AMR + Loc 1 Admiral Loc. 442, 1953-1959 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Arbitration 1968 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Arbitration 1968 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Arbitration 1968 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Arbitration 1968 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Arbitration 1969 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Non-arbitration files. Contains legal petitions, briefs, appeal records, transcripts, etc. (Box 10)
  - A.A. Tube Testing Co. v. Sohne (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Mt. Vernon Amusement Co. v. Georgian Restaurant Corp. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - CNS Taverns, Inc. v. Arnold (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Herman Automatic Music Group v. Lenric Restaurant Corp. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Rye Cliff Apartments v. Stickel (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - John & Associates v. Choate (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Music Operators of NY v. Mortimer Pearl (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Morgan Builders, Inc. v. Ginza Inc. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - NLRB v. Ford Radio & Mica Corporation - US Court of Appeals Joint Appendix (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - NLRB v. Ford Radio & Mica Corporation - Briefs (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Decicco v. Viviano Briefs (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Decicco v. Viviano - Record on Appeal (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Pace v. Pace - Plaintiff Briefs (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Pace v. Pace - Respondent Briefs (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Pace v. Pace - Case on Appeals (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Pace v. Pace - Pretrial Examination of Defendant (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Pace v. Pace - Record on Appeal (Original) (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Pace v. Pace - Record on Appeal (Copy) (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Kessler v. Hunter - Briefs for Plaintiff (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Kessler v. Hunter - Briefs for Defendant (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Kessler v. Hunter - Record on Appeal (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Kessler v. Hunter - Record on Appeal (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Kessler v. Hunter - Record on Appeal (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Pace v. Pace & ECAP Holding Corp. - Case on Appeal (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Cases (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Non-arbitration files. Contains legal petitions, briefs, appeal records, transcripts, etc. (Box 11)
  - John & Associates v. Choate Record on Appeal (Copies) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - John & Associates v. Choate Record on Appeal (Originals) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - A.A. Tube Testing Co. v. Sohne (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Kessler v. Hunter (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Kessler v. Hunter Transcripts (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Mt. Vernon Amusement v. Georgian Restaurant Corp. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Suffridge v. Lasky (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Music Operators of NY v. Mortimer Pearl: Pre-Trial Examination of Cohen v. Cagiano (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Local 1115 v. La Royale, Inc. Arbitration - pg. 1-103 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Local 1115 v. La Royale, Inc. Arbitration - pg. 104-220 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - John & Associates v. Choate Briefs (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Pace v. Pace Briefs (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Pace v. Pace - Trial Term, Part V (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - NLRB: Automatic Sealing Service, Inc. - Transcript pg. 1-207 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - NLRB: Automatic Sealing Service, Inc. - Transcript pg. 209-511 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - NLRB: Automatic Sealing Services, Inc. - Transcript pg. 521-667 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - NLRB: Automatic Sealing Service, Inc. - Transcript pg. 668-750; 816-900 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Before the Intersatate Commerce Commission No. MC-F 5315 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - State of New York Cases (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Supreme Court of the State of New York, Westchester County (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - New York Supreme Court - Fairchester Realty - Petitioner's Memorandum (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - NY State Supreme Court - Fairchester Realty - Briefs (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - NY Supreme Court Appellate Division - Fairchester Realty - Papers on Appeal (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous Cases (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Articles (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Motion to Dismiss: Lack of Prosecution (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Arbitration Confirmation (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Judgment CDLR 3215 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Vacate Arbitration (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Pre-Trial Witnesses (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Declaratory Judging (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Motion to Dismiss - Pleading (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Articles (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Non-arbitration files. Contains legal petitions, briefs, appeal records, transcripts, etc. (Box 12)
  - United States of America v. Matthias Kohler (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Matthias Kohler v. United States of America (Appeal) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - United States of America v. August Klapprott (1 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - United States of America v. August Klapprott (2 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - United States of America v. August Klapprott (3 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - United States of America v. Winfield E. Richards (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - United States of America v. Backofen (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - United States of America v. Bruno Peter Johann Koop (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - United States of America v. George Neupert (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - City Council of Rye, New York (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - City of Rye, New York (continued) (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - City of Rye, New York (continued) (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Briefs and Documents for Trial Examiners (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Wertheimer Stores Corporation and NLRB (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Labor Arbitration Information (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - New York University Dissertations/Thesis (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Gatto Engraving Company, Inc. and Public National Bank & Trust Company of New York (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous Files. Includes papers collected re Planning Commission, City of Rye; Handwritten notes, clippings, releases, memos, publications re National Academy of Arbitrators, PERB, OCB and other miscellaneous. (Box 13)
  - Misc., 1958-1968 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Misc., 1962-1967 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - OLB, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - NAA, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Restaurant Info, 1960-1965 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - NAA, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - NAA, 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - NAA, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - NAA, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - NAA, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - PERB, 1968-1970 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - PERB, 1968-1970 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - PERB (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - PERB, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - PERB, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - PERB, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Gatto Engraving Co. Profit Sharing Plan, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Gatto Engraving Co. Profit Sharing Plan, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 17)